Dr. Timothy R. White Curriculum Vitae

Institut für Astrophysik, Georg-August-Universität Göttingen Friedrich-Hund-Platz 1, 37077 Göttingen **Phone:** +49 (0)551 392 046

Email: twhite@astro.physik.uni-goettingen.de

Research

My research has found me at the intersection of the fields of asteroseismology and long-baseline optical interferometry. These are two of the most powerful techniques of modern stellar astrophysics, made possible due to recent advances in instrumentation. I have made use of data provided by the NASA Space Telescope *Kepler* to study stellar oscillations and used the PAVO instrument at the CHARA interferometric array on Mt Wilson, California to precisely determine the parameters of several *Kepler* stars. By studying the oscillations of stars asteroseismically, and measuring angular diameters with interferometry, fundamental stellar parameters such as mass, radius, and effective temperature may be determined with great precision and accuracy. Determining these constraints is crucial for testing stellar models, through which we understand stellar structure and evolution.

Academic Positions

Oct 2013 – present: Postdoctoral Researcher at the Institut für Astrophysik,

Georg-August-Universität Göttingen

August 2013: Postdoctoral Research Assistant at the Stellar Astrophysics Centre,

Department of Physics and Astronomy, Aarhus University

2010-2012: Postgraduate Teaching Fellow at the School of Physics, University of Sydney

Education

2010-2013: Doctor of Philosophy, School of Physics, The University of Sydney and

Australian Astronomical Observatory

Thesis Title: Asteroseismology of Sun-Like Stars with Kepler Supervisors: Tim Bedding, Dennis Stello, Simon O'Toole

Degree Conferred: 30 May 2014

2006-2009: Bachelor of Science (Advanced) (Honours), The University of Sydney

Majors: Physics and Applied Mathematics

Thesis Title: Frequency Analysis of the Rapidly Oscillating Ap Star HR1217

Supervisors: Tim Bedding, Dennis Stello, Brendon Brewer Final Result: Honours Class I and the University Medal

Degree Conferred: 28 May 2010

Scholarships and Awards

2010-2013: Australian Postgraduate Award

University of Sydney Merit Award

Denison Merit Award

2010-2012: Australian Astronomical Observatory PhD Scholarship

2009: Henry Chamberlain Russell Prize in Astronomy2008: Deas-Thomson Scholarship in Physics (shared)

School of Physics - Julius Sumner Miller Scholarships for

Academic Excellence No.3 (Shared)

Walter Burfitt Scholarship No II for Physics (shared)

Placed on the Dean's List of Excellence in Academic Performance

2007: Science Foundation for Physics Scholarship No II

2006: Placed on the Dean's List of Excellence in Academic Performance

Publications

• 31 Publications in refereed journals; 6 as first author.

Over 1100 citations with a Hirsch-index of 18

Refereed Papers:

- 1. G. W. Marcy, & 102 co-authors including T. R. White. 2014, ApJS, 210, 20.
- 2. T. Arentoft, B. Tingley, J. Christensen-Dalsgaard, H. Kjeldsen, **T. R. White**, F. Grundahl. 2014, MNRAS, 437, 1318.
- 3. V. Maestro, & 10 co-authors including **T. R. White**. 2013, MNRAS, 434, 1321.
- 4. T. R. White, D. Huber, V. Maestro, et al. 2013, MNRAS, 433, 1262.
- 5. V. Silva Aguirre, & 23 co-authors inlcuding T. R. White. 2013, ApJ, 769, 141.
- 6. O. Benomar, & 9 co-authors including **T. R. White**. 2013, ApJ, 767, 169.
- 7. D. Stello, & 9 co-authors including **T. R. White**. 2013, ApJ, 765, L41.
- 8. D. Huber, & 39 co-authors including **T. R. White**. 2012, ApJ, 760, 32.
- 9. E. Corsaro, & 21 co-authors including T. R. White. 2012, ApJ, 757, 190.
- 10. T. Appourchaux, & 27 co-authors including T. R. White. 2012, A&A, 543, A54.
- 11. D. Huber, & 15 co-authors including **T. R. White**. 2012, MNRAS, 432, L16.
- 12. **T. R. White**, T. R. Bedding, M. Gruberbauer, et al. 2012, ApJ, 751, L36.
- 13. S. Mathur, & 41 co-authors including **T. R. White**. 2012, ApJ, 749, 152.
- 14. S. B. Howell, & 66 co-authors including **T. R. White**. 2012, ApJ, 746, 123.
- 15. O. Benomar, T. R. Bedding, D. Stello, S. Deheuvels, **T. R. White**, J. Christensen-Dalsgaard. 2012, ApJ, 745, L33.

- 16. T. Appourchaux, & 22 co-authors including T. R. White. 2012, A&A, 537, A134.
- 17. O. Creevey, & 36 co-authors including **T. R. White**. 2012, A&A, 537, A111.
- 18. **T. R. White**, T. R. Bedding, D. Stello, J. Christensen-Dalsgaard, D. Huber, H. Kjeldsen, 2011, ApJ, 743, 161.
- 19. **T. R. White**, T. R. Bedding, D. Stello, et al. 2011, ApJ, 742, L3.
- 20. V. Silva Aguirre, & 41 co-authors inlcuding T. R. White. 2011, ApJ, 740, L2.
- 21. T. L. Campante, & 35 co-authors inlouding T. R. White. 2011, A&A, 534, A6.
- 22. G. A. Verner, & 26 co-authors inlouding T. R. White. 2011, MNRAS, 415, 3539.
- 23. **T. R. White**, T, R. Bedding, D. Stello, D. W. Kurtz, M. S. Cunha, D. O. Gough, 2011, MNRAS, 415, 1638.
- 24. L. A. Balona, & 10 co-authors inlcuding T. R. White. 2011, MNRAS, 413, 2651.
- 25. S. Mathur, & 36 co-authors inlouding T. R. White. 2011, ApJ, 733, 95.
- 26. W. J. Chaplin, & 58 co-authors inlcuding T. R. White. 2011, Science, 332, 213.
- 27. P. G. Beck, & 25 co-authors inlcuding T. R. White. 2011, Science, 332, 205.
- 28. T. R. Bedding, & 33 co-authors inlcuding **T. R. White**. 2011, Nature, 471, 608.
- 29. D. Huber, & 21 co-authors inlouding T. R. White. 2011, ApJ, 723, 1607.
- 30. T. S. Metcalfe, & 57 co-authors inlouding T. R. White. 2010, ApJ, 723, 1583.
- 31. **T. R. White**, B. J. Brewer, T. R. Bedding, D. Stello, H. Kjeldsen, 2010, Communications in Asteroseismology, 161, 39.

Presentations

- 1. Measuring stellar properties with asteroseismology and interferometry
 Solar Group Seminar, 29 April 2014, Max Planck Institute for Solar System Research, Göttingen, Germany.
- 3. Testing asteroseismic scaling relations with interferometry
 Stellar Astrophysics Centre Seminar, 3 September 2013, Aarhus University, Denmark.
- Asteroseismology of Sun-Like Stars with Kepler Sydney Institute for Astronomy Seminar, 26 July 2013, University of Sydney, Australia.
- 5. The large separation and its scaling relation
 Sixth Kepler Asteroseismic Science Consortium Workshop, 24 June 2013, Sydney, Australia.
- Kepler observations of the asteroseismic binary HD 176465
 Fifth Kepler Asteroseismic Science Consortium Workshop, 19 June 2012, Balatonalmadi, Hungary.

- 7. Kepler observations of the asteroseismic binary HD 176465
 The Astornomical Society of Australia Annual Scientific Meeting, 2 July 2012, University of New South Wales, Sydney, Australia.
- 8. *Kepler observations of the asteroseismic binary HD 176465*Fifth Kepler Asteroseismic Science Consortium Workshop, 19 June 2012, Balatonalmadi, Hungary.
- Ensemble asteroseismology of solar-like oscillations
 Jeremiah Horrocks Institute Seminar, 6 June 2012, University of Central Lancashire, Preston, United Kingdom.
- Ensemble asteroseismology of solar-like oscillations
 The Modern Era of Helio- and Asteroseismology, ESF-LFUI Reserach Conference, 21 May 2012, Obergurgl, Austria.
- 11. Ensemble asteroseismology of solar-like oscillations
 Stellar Astrophysics Centre Seminar, 15 May 2012, Aarhus University, Denmark.
- 12. Curing HD 49933 syndrome: resolving the mode identification problem in F stars Sydney Institute for Astronomy Morning Tea, 25 July 2011, University of Sydney, Australia.
- 13. Curing HD 49933 syndrome: resolving the mode identification problem in F stars Fourth Kepler Asteroseismic Science Consortium Workshop, 11 July 2011, Boulder, Colorado, USA.
- Ensemble asteroseismology of solar-like oscillations
 AAO 2010 Student Symposium, 26 October 2010, Australian Astronomical Observatory, Sydney, Australia.
- Ensemble asteroseismology of solar-like oscillations
 Sydney Institute for Astronomy Morning Tea, 16 August 2010, University of Sydney, Australia.
- Ensemble asteroseismology of solar-like oscillations
 Sydney Astronomy and Astrophysics Students Symposium, 18 June 2010, University of New South Wales, Sydney, Australia.